<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div data-template="pages:load">
        <div id="static-title" class="hidden">Open Government Initiative</div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
                <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app">Home</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/open">Open Government Initiative</a>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds">
                <div id="content-inner" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <h1>Open Government Initiative</h1>
                    <p>Transparency, participation, and collaboration are the foundation of open
                        government. In keeping with this principle established in the Open
                        Government Directive, the Office of the Historian has adapted its
                        publications to open digital formats that can be accessed and consumed
                        easily by the public, including third party developers. The Office of the
                        Historian made the following submissions to data.gov, which remain up to
                        date: <ol>
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/open/frus-metadata">Bibliographic Metadata of the
                                        <em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em> Series</a>:
                                Raw bibliographic metadata for the nearly 500 volumes in the <em>
                                    <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/">Foreign Relations of the
                                        United States</a>
                                </em> series published since 1861. Each record in the dataset
                                contains a volume’s title, year of publication, years covered by the
                                volume, summary, and links to sources for these volumes online or in
                                print, among other metadata items. [<a
                                    href="https://catalog.data.gov/dataset/bibliographical-metadata-of-the-foreign-relations-of-the-united-states-series"
                                    >Data.gov catalog entry</a>]</li>
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/open/frus-latest">Latest Volumes of <em>Foreign
                                        Relations of the United States</em> Series</a>: This atom
                                feed lists the ten most recently published volumes in the <a
                                    href="$app/historicaldocuments/">Foreign Relations of the United
                                    States</a> series. Each record in the dataset contains a
                                volume’s title, year of publication, summary, and link to the online
                                volumes. The feed is updated as soon as a new volume is published.
                                    [<a
                                    href="https://catalog.data.gov/dataset/latest-volumes-of-foreign-relations-of-the-united-states"
                                    >Data.gov catalog entry</a>]</li>
                        </ol>
                    </p>
                    <p>Building on this foundation and extending the focus beyond data, the Digital
                        Government Strategy emphasized delivering better digital services to the
                        American people government through mobile devices and providing automated
                        services for third party web and app developers. The Office of the Historian
                        made the following contributions to the Digital Government Strategy: <ol>
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/ebooks">Ebook Editions of Office
                                    of the Historian Publications</a>: The <em>Foreign Relations of
                                    the United States</em> (<em>FRUS</em>) series, established in
                                1861, was adapted to ebook. Far lighter and more portable than
                                printed editions of <em>FRUS</em>, the ebook edition offers the full
                                content of each volume and makes use of the full-text search and
                                other reading features of most ebook devices and applications,
                                including bookmarking and note-taking. Unlike the web-based edition
                                of <em>FRUS</em>, the ebook edition, once downloaded, can be
                                accessed even without internet connectivity. The ebooks were
                                generated from the master digital files at no additional cost and
                                are available for free download.</li>
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/developer/catalog">Office of the Historian Ebook
                                    Catalog API</a>: This <a
                                    href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_programming_interface"
                                    >Application Programming Interface</a> (API) enables third party
                                web and app developers, as well as users of these applications, to
                                embed the Office of the Historian ebook catalog. The API uses best
                                practices and open standards, including the <a
                                    href="http://opds-spec.org">Open Publication Distribution
                                    System</a> (OPDS) format for ebook catalogs and REST
                                interfaces.</li>
                        </ol>
                    </p>
                    <p>For more information, see the <a
                            href="https://www.state.gov/open-government-initiative/">Open Government
                            Initiative</a>, <a
                            href="https://www.state.gov/digital-government-strategy/">Digital
                            Government Strategy</a>, and <a href="https://www.state.gov/developer/"
                            >Developer Community</a> pages on the Department of State’s website.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <aside class="hsg-width-one-third">
                <div id="sections" class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Open Government Initiative</h2>
                    </div>
                    <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/open/frus-metadata">Bibliographic Metadata of the
                                    <em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em> Series</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/open/frus-latest">Latest Volumes of <em>Foreign Relations
                                    of the United States</em> Series</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </aside>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
