<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div data-template="pages:load">
        <div id="static-title" class="hidden">Archives - Countries</div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
                <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app">Home</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/countries">Countries</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/countries/archives">Archives</a>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds">
                <div id="content-inner" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <h1>World Wide Diplomatic Archives Index</h1>
                    <p>The Office of the Historian has for many years provided researchers a guide
                        to the accessibility of diplomatic archives around the world. This current
                        list is based on information received from American diplomatic posts abroad,
                        as well as web sources and communication with the archives themselves. The
                        information provided here is subject to change so researchers are advised to
                        contact the government or archive ahead of any planned visit. </p>
                    <p>Select an article from the list of <a href="$app/countries/archives/all">all
                            countries</a>.</p>
                    <p>While access to the diplomatic records of many countries remains highly
                        restricted, the news is better than ever before with many new countries
                        establishing Freedom of Information Acts to foment better government
                        transparency. </p>
                    <p>The divide between the developed world and the developing world also affects
                        the state of international archives. Problems of infrastructure inhibit the
                        nature of information dissemination. The amount of information available on
                        the internet varies from country to country and many National Archives and
                        Ministries of Foreign Affairs are still in the process of developing
                        workable websites.</p>
                    <p>This site does not comment on the state of the records themselves. In
                        addition to the loss of records as a result of changes of government and
                        civil war, the climate has wreaked havoc upon some archives, particularly in
                        tropical regions, whose documents, despite the best efforts of archivists,
                        have been compromised by heat, humidity, flooding, and frequent power
                        outages.</p>
                    <p>In compiling this database, the Office of the Historian has tried to give
                        researchers a starting place for their inquiries. We have not included
                        anecdotal advice on how to approach any given archive. Countries that do not
                        systematically declassify their documents may require personal contacts to
                        gain access to records of interest. Additionally, compliance with laws that
                        guide freedom of information may vary.</p>
                    <p>For the most part, diplomatic records are held by the Ministry of Foreign
                        Affairs (or a similar department) or have been transferred to a National
                        Archive. If that is done systematically, it is usually apparent as to which
                        records are available for viewing. When transfer is not systematic, it is up
                        to the researcher to discover the location of the documents they wish to
                        view as well as to make contact with the relevant archivist.</p>
                    <p>The Office of the Historian would be happy to receive updated or missing
                        information. Please <a href="$app/about/contact-us">contact us</a>.</p>
                    <p>Other relevant websites with useful information on diplomatic archives
                        include: </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <a
                                href="http://www.unesco.org/new/en/communication-and-information/portals-and-platforms/unesco-archives-portal/"
                                >UNESCOs archive portal</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a
                                href="http://archivesmadeeasy.pbworks.com/w/page/24292744/LSE%20Archives"
                                >Archives Made Easy based at the London School of Economics and
                                Political Science</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a
                                href="https://europa.eu/european-union/about-eu/countries/member-countries_en"
                                >EU Member Countries</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a href="http://africa-research.org/">Repositories of African
                                Archives</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a href="https://www.ica.org/en">International Council on Archives</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a
                                href="https://www.diplomatie.gouv.fr/en/the-ministry-and-its-network/archives-and-heritage/colonne-droite/association-of-friends-of-the/article/association-des-amis-des-archives"
                                >Association of Friends of the Diplomatic Archives</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a href="http://archiveswiki.historians.org/">Archives Wiki</a> created
                            by the American Historical Association</li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </div>
            <aside class="hsg-width-one-third">
                <div class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Archives</h2>
                    </div>
                    <div class="hsg-panel-body">
                        <p>
                            <a href="$app/countries/archives/all">List of all countries in the World
                                Wide Diplomatic Archives Index</a>
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Related Resources</h2>
                    </div>
                    <div class="hsg-panel-body">
                        <p>
                            <a href="$app/countries">Countries</a>
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </aside>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
