<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-at="content"
    data-template-with="templates/site.xml">
    <div class="hidden" id="static-title">About the Foreign Relations Series - Historical
        Documents</div>
    <div class="row">
        <div data-template="pages:breadcrumb">
            <p id="breadcrumb-title">About the <em>Foreign Relations</em> Series</p>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="row hsg-main">
        <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds" data-template="app:fix-links">
            <div id="content-inner">
                <h1>About the <em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em> Series</h1>
                <p>The Department of State has published the <a href="$app/historicaldocuments"
                        ><em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em> (FRUS) series</a>, the
                    official documentary record of U.S. foreign policy, since 1861. The Office of
                    the Historian (OH) prepares the series under the requirements established by
                    Public Law 102-138 (105 Stat. 647, codified in relevant part at 22 U.S.C. § 4351
                    et seq.), enacted in 1991 and amended in 2021, which specifies that the
                    Historian of the Department of State is responsible for the preparation of the
                    series. To ensure that FRUS is “a thorough, accurate, and reliable documentary
                    record of major United States foreign policy decisions and significant United
                    States diplomatic activity,” the statute requires OH to make use of
                    documentation from across the national security establishment and directs United
                    States Government departments, agencies, and other entities to provide OH
                    historians full and complete access to pertinent records at 20 years. The
                    statute also mandates publication of volumes 30 years after the events they
                    document.</p>
                <p>Under the direction of the General Editor of the FRUS series, OH historians plan
                    the overall scope and content of the series, and research, compile, and edit
                    individual volumes according to guidelines established in 1925 by Secretary of
                    State Frank Kellogg and codified in the FRUS statute. These include: that the
                    editing of records selected for inclusion in the series shall be guided by the
                    principles of historical objectivity and accuracy; that records should not be
                    altered or deletions made without indicating in the published text that a
                    deletion has been made; that the published record should omit no facts that were
                    of major importance in reaching a decision; and that nothing should be omitted
                    for the purposes of concealing a defect in policy.</p>
                <p>FRUS documents the history of U.S. bilateral and regional relations; global
                    issues such as terrorism, narcotics, health, and the environment; and topics
                    such as national security policy, foreign economic policy, and foreign policy
                    organization and management. The series is a highly visible manifestation of the
                    U.S. Government’s commitment to responsible transparency, providing U.S.
                    citizens an understanding of historical foreign policies. Based upon research in
                    the records of the White House, National Security Council, Departments of State
                    and Defense, Central Intelligence Agency, and other foreign affairs agencies, as
                    well as the private papers of individual U.S. foreign policymakers, FRUS
                    illuminates how U.S. decision makers determined foreign policy and what that
                    policy aimed to achieve, increasing understanding of the United States and its
                    role in the world among scholars, the public, and the international community.
                    The series offers important insight into the origins of contemporary challenges,
                    serving the national interest by providing a sound basis of historical context
                    to support current policymaking. The international reach of FRUS has proven
                    valuable to U.S. efforts to shape global norms of historical transparency and
                    offers citizens of many nations an important source for an accurate
                    understanding of their own histories.</p>
            </div>
        </div>
        <aside data-template="pages:asides">
            <div class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                    <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Administrations</h2>
                </div>
                <div class="hsg-panel-body">
                    <p>Browse official documents from the <em>Foreign Relations of the United
                            States</em> series.</p>
                </div>
                <div class="hsg-panel-heading-second-level">
                    <h3 class="hsg-sidebar-title-second-level">Recent Administrations</h3>
                </div>
                <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/kennedy">Kennedy Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/johnson">Johnson Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/nixon-ford">Nixon-Ford Administrations</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/carter">Carter Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/reagan">Reagan Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/bush-ghw">Bush Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/clinton">Clinton Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments">All Administrations</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </aside>
    </div>
</div>
