<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div class="row">
        <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
            <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                <li>
                    <a href="$app">Home</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="$app/historicaldocuments">Historical Documents</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/ebooks">Ebooks</a>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="row hsg-main" data-template="pages:load">
        <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds" data-template="app:fix-links">
            <div id="content-inner">
                <h2>Ebooks</h2>
                <p>The Office of the Historian offers ebook editions of a growing number of volumes
                    from the <em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em> (<em>FRUS</em>) series.
                    Far lighter and more portable than printed editions of <em>FRUS</em>, the ebook
                    edition offers the full content of each volume and makes use of the full-text
                    search and other reading features of most ebook devices and applications,
                    including bookmarking and note-taking. Unlike the web-based edition of
                        <em>FRUS</em>, the ebook edition, once downloaded, can be accessed even
                    without internet connectivity.</p>
                <p>These ebooks can be downloaded in a number of ways, either directly from this
                    website or by using an ereader application that embeds our ebook catalog. For
                    more information on reading our ebooks on your device, please see our <a
                        href="#faq">FAQ</a> below.</p>
                <p>The Office of the Historian has worked to ensure that our ebooks are error-free
                    and work on a broad range of devices. Please email <a
                        href="mailto:history_ebooks@state.gov?subject=FRUS%20Ebooks%20Feedback&amp;body=Your%20e-reader%3A%0A%0AVolume%3A%0A%0AComments%3A"
                        >history_ebooks@state.gov</a> with any feedback.</p>
                <div id="catalog" data-template="frus:frus-ebooks-catalog"/>
                <div id="faq">
                    <h3>FAQ</h3>
                    <h4>Accessing Ebooks</h4>
                    <ul id="tested-devices-and-apps">
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Q: What e-reader devices and
                            apps have <em>FRUS</em> ebooks been tested with?</li>
                        <li>A: We have tested <em>FRUS</em> ebooks on a range of devices and apps:
                            iOS applications include iBooks, ShuBook, MegaReader, Kobo, Bluefire
                            Reader, Subtext, and the Kindle app. Kindle devices include the Keyboard
                            and Fire models. Android apps include Bluefire and Alkido. We encourage
                            users of other devices and apps to report their experiences.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <ul id="adding-ebooks-to-devices">
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Q: How can I add a
                                <em>FRUS</em> ebook to my device?</li>
                        <li>A: Until <em>FRUS</em> ebooks are available through commercial ebook
                            retailers, there are two primary methods for adding a <em>FRUS</em>
                            ebook to your device: (1) “Side-loading” an ebook from this website onto
                            your device or (2) Using an application that embeds our catalog and lets
                            you browse and download directly from the application. It is important
                            to understand what methods and apps are available on your device.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <h4 id="side-loading">“Side-loading” <em>FRUS</em> Ebooks</h4>
                    <ul>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Q: How can I load “side-load”
                            ebooks onto my device?</li>
                        <li>A: Consult the instructions provided by your app developer or device
                            manufacturer to “side-load” the ebook file into your e-reader.<br/>
                            <ul style="list-style-type: disc; padding-above: .5em">
                                <li>
                                    <strong>iBooks (Apple iOS):</strong> Select “Can I download
                                    books from other websites?” under “Managing your books and
                                    iBookstore content” from the <a
                                        href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201478">iBooks:
                                        Frequently Asked Questions</a>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    <strong>Amazon Kindle:</strong> Search <a
                                        href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/?nodeId=200127470"
                                        >Kindle Support</a> for “transferring” and select
                                    instructions specific to your device/app</li>
                                <li>
                                    <strong>Barnes &amp; Noble Nook:</strong> Search <a
                                        href="https://help.barnesandnoble.com/app/nook_support/list"
                                        >Nook Support</a> for “sideloading” and select instructions
                                    specific to your device/app</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <h4 id="embedding-the-catalog">Embedding our Ebook Catalog in Apps</h4>
                    <ul>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Q: How can I add the Office
                            of the Historian’s ebook catalog to my favorite ebook app?</li>
                        <li>A: A growing number of apps support the OPDS standard, allowing these
                            apps to embed the Office of the Historian’s ebook catalog and offer
                            browsing, downloading, and reading within the application. The Office of
                            the Historian’s ebook catalog URL (an OPDS API) is <a
                                href="https://history.state.gov/api/v1/catalog"
                                >https://history.state.gov/api/v1/catalog</a>. To add our catalog to
                            your OPDS-compliant ebook application, consult the directions, and enter
                            this URL where directed. We have tested ShuBook and MegaReader on iOS
                            and the IbisReader web application. Please submit your feedback about
                            these or other applications to <a
                                href="mailto:history_ebooks@state.gov?subject=FRUS%20EBooks%20Feedback&amp;body=Your%20e-reader%3A%0A%0AVolume%3A%0A%0AComments%3A"
                                >history_ebooks@state.gov</a>.</li>
                        <li>If you are a developer of ebook applications and would like to
                            incorporate the Office of the Historian ebook catalog into your
                            application, please see our <a href="$app/developer">Developer
                                Resources</a> page.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <h4 id="citing-frus-ebooks">Citing <em>FRUS</em> EBooks</h4>
                    <ul>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Q: Since ebooks do not have
                            stable page numbers, how can I cite references to <em>FRUS</em>
                            ebooks?</li>
                        <li>A: Use document numbers rather than page numbers. Document numbers are
                            persistent, media-neutral identifiers. For example, to cite <a
                                href="$app/historicaldocuments/frus1969-76v32/d262">this
                                memorandum</a> from the <em>SALT I, 1969-1972</em> volume, use:
                                <blockquote style="font-style: normal; margin: 1em">U.S. Department
                                of State, <em>Foreign Relations of the United States,
                                    1969-1976,</em> Vol. XXXII, <em>SALT I, 1969-1972</em>
                                (Washington, DC: U.S. Government Printing Office, 2010),
                                    <strong>Doc. 262</strong>.</blockquote> rather than <blockquote
                                style="font-style: normal; margin: 1em">U.S. Department of State,
                                    <em>Foreign Relations of the United States, 1969-1976,</em> Vol.
                                XXXII, <em>SALT I, 1969-1972</em> (Washington, DC: U.S. Government
                                Printing Office, 2010), <strong>774-781</strong>.</blockquote>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <h4 id="known-issues">Known Issues</h4>
                    <ul>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Issue: <em>FRUS</em> ebook
                            footnote behavior on Kindle devices and the Kindle app.</li>
                        <li>Description: Footnotes are hyperlinked in <em>FRUS</em> ebooks so that
                            activating a footnote reference will navigate directly to the text of
                            the footnote (and vice versa). On Kindle devices and apps, activating
                            the hyperlink from the footnote text back to the footnote reference in
                            the document will navigate to the content immediately following the
                            reference.</li>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Issue: Indexes in pre-Johnson
                            era <em>FRUS</em> refer to page numbers rather than document
                            numbers</li>
                        <li>In creating the <em>FRUS</em> ebook edition, we endeavored to maintain
                            fidelity with the original printed edition. Representing original page
                            numbers from printed editions in ebooks has proved to be difficult. For
                            readers who need to cite material in this ebook, we recommend citing
                            document numbers instead of page numbers. Document numbers are
                            persistent, media-neutral identifiers. Please note that since the
                            indexes in older <em>FRUS</em> volumes refer to page numbers rather than
                            document numbers, we have found certain indexes cannot be used “as is”
                            in ebook versions and so have been omitted from the ebook edition of
                            pre-Johnson administration volumes. Volumes from the Johnson
                            administration onward, whose indexes reference document numbers, are
                            unaffected by this issue.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <h4 id="helpful-tips">Helpful Tips</h4>
                    <ul>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Tip: Using bookmarks.</li>
                        <li>Description: Many e-readers allow users to set multiple bookmarks and
                            navigate to them quickly from an easily-accessible list of all the
                            assigned bookmarks in a given ebook. <em>FRUS</em> ebook users can take
                            advantage of this feature to place bookmarks on frequently-used
                            resources, like the Persons, Source, and/or the Terms and Abbreviations
                            lists that are located at the beginning of each volume. Many e-readers
                            also allow you to jump back to a previous location, making it easy to
                            take advantage of the information in a <em>FRUS</em> ebook’s front
                            matter without losing your place in the volume.</li>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Tip: Using the table of
                            contents.</li>
                        <li>Description: In addition to a hyperlinked version of the table of
                            contents listing chapters in the compilation that appears in the
                            beginning pages of a printed <em>FRUS</em> volume, <em>FRUS</em> ebooks
                            provide users with richly detailed lists of individual documents and
                            their source notes at the beginning of each chapter and in the general
                            table of contents accessible via the e-reader’s table of contents
                            feature.</li>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Tip: Using full-text
                            search.</li>
                        <li>Description: Like the volumes accessible on <a href="$app"
                                >history.state.gov</a>, <em>FRUS</em> ebooks are fully
                            text-searchable. The features and behavior of the search engine depends
                            on your e-reader device/app.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <h4 id="feedback">Providing Feedback or Other Questions</h4>
                    <ul>
                        <li style="font-weight: bold; padding: .5em 0">Q: How can I provide feedback
                            or ask a question not answered here?</li>
                        <li>A: We welcome your feedback or other questions not answered here. Please
                            contact us at <a
                                href="mailto:history_ebooks@state.gov?subject=FRUS%20EBooks%20Feedback&amp;body=Your%20e-reader%3A%0A%0AVolume%3A%0A%0AComments%3A"
                                >history_ebooks@state.gov</a>.</li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <aside class="hsg-width-one-third">
            <div class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                    <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Historical Documents</h2>
                </div>
                <div class="hsg-panel-body">
                    <p>Browse official documents from the <em>Foreign Relations of the United
                            States</em> series.</p>
                </div>
                <div class="hsg-panel-heading-second-level">
                    <h3 class="hsg-sidebar-title-second-level">Recent Administrations</h3>
                </div>
                <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/kennedy">Kennedy Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/johnson">Johnson Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/nixon-ford">Nixon-Ford Administrations</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/carter">Carter Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/reagan">Reagan Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/bush-ghw">Bush Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/clinton">Clinton Administration</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments">All Administrations</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </div>

            <div id="sections" class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                    <h3 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Related Resources</h3>
                </div>

                <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/about-frus">About the <em>Foreign
                                Relations</em> series</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/status-of-the-series">Status of the
                            Series</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/frus-history">History of the Series</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/ebooks">
                            <em>Foreign Relations</em> ebooks</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/other-electronic-resources">Other
                            Electronic resources for U.S. foreign relations</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/guide-to-sources-on-vietnam-1969-1975"
                            >Guide to sources on Vietnam, 1969-1975</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/search/tips">Tips for searching the <em>Foreign Relations</em>
                            Series</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="$app/historicaldocuments/citing-frus">How to cite <em>Foreign
                                Relations</em> documents</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </aside>
    </div>
</div>
