<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div data-template="pages:load">
        <div id="static-title" class="hidden">Into Moscow - U.S. Diplomatic Couriers - Department
            History</div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
                <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app">Home</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory">Department History</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory/diplomatic-couriers">U.S. Diplomatic
                            Couriers</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory/diplomatic-couriers/into-moscow">Into
                            Moscow</a>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds">
                <div id="content-inner" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <h1>U.S. Diplomatic Couriers: Into Moscow</h1>
                    <!-- Start of Brightcove Player -->
                    <div style="position: relative; display: block;">
                        <div style="padding-top: 56.25%;">
                            <video data-video-id="5798847904001" data-account="1705665025"
                                data-player="HJ8lQG1Eg" data-embed="default"
                                data-application-id="data-application-id" class="video-js"
                                controls="controls"
                                style="position: absolute; top: 0px; right: 0px; bottom: 0px; left: 0px; width: 100%; height: 100%;"/>
                            <script
                                src="https://players.brightcove.net/1705665025/HJ8lQG1Eg_default/index.min.js"
                            />
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <!-- End of Brightcove Player -->
                    <div id="synopsis">
                        <h2>Synopsis</h2>
                        <p>In the 1950s, Diplomatic Couriers traveled tens of thousands of miles per
                            year, crossing borders both geographic and cultural. The United States
                            and the USSR, once allied at the end of World War II, had become
                            adversaries in what became known as the Cold War, as Soviet power crept
                            further west across Europe. Events like the 1948 Communist coup in
                            Czechoslovakia and the Soviet blockade of West Berlin in 1948–1949
                            caused U.S officials to grow increasingly wary of the possibility that
                            Western European leaders might deal with their security concerns by
                            negotiating with Stalin and the Soviet Union.</p>
                        <p>The Truman administration looked to military alliances and humanitarian
                            assistance to bolster the security and prosperity of Western Europe and
                            cement Euro-Atlantic ties. The <a href="$app/milestones/1945-1952/nato"
                                >North Atlantic Treaty</a> signed in 1949 brought the United States,
                            Canada, and much of Western Europe into a collective security alliance. 
                            The <a href="$app/milestones/1945-1952/marshall-plan">Marshall Plan</a>,
                            proposed by Secretary of State George C. Marshall, directed $12 billion
                            toward the rebuilding of Western Europe, regenerating industrialization
                            and bringing extensive investment into the region.</p>
                        <p>The Soviet refusal either to participate in the Marshall Plan or to allow
                            its satellite states in Eastern Europe to accept the economic assistance
                            helped to reinforce the growing division between the East and the West
                            in Europe. The U.S. Diplomatic Couriers felt acutely this division as
                            they carried diplomatic pouches from behind the Iron Curtain in Western
                            Germany to our missions in Budapest and Bucharest, and from Helsinki
                            into the Soviet Union to support the U.S. Embassy in Moscow. The
                            couriers traveled in pairs to ensure their own safety and the security
                            of the diplomatic pouches.</p>
                        <p>During this era, the U.S. Diplomatic Couriers provided service to the
                            U.S. Embassy in Moscow from Helsinki. This “Helsinki Detail” was often a
                            3- or 4-week detail during which the couriers would take turns
                            collecting and delivering the diplomatic pouches from the mail hub in
                            Frankfurt, Germany, up to Helsinki, Finland, then into the Soviet Union.
                            Couriers traveled by air several times a week, carrying smaller pouches
                            on Aeroflot or SAS flights directly into Moscow. In order to bring in
                            larger loads, the couriers made monthly train trips through Leningrad
                            into Moscow.  Depending on flight or train schedules, the couriers often
                            spent several days off-duty in Moscow.</p>
                        <p>In this short documentary, the U.S. Diplomatic Couriers talk about the
                            journey and their personal impressions of what it was like to travel
                            into Moscow during this era.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div id="more-information">
                        <h2>More information</h2>
                        <dl>
                            <dt>Released</dt>
                            <dd>2018</dd>
                            <dt>Length</dt>
                            <dd>26:12</dd>
                            <dt>Creator</dt>
                            <dd>Rebecca A. Ross, Foreign Service Officer, U.S. Department of
                                State</dd>
                        </dl>
                    </div>
                    <div id="transcript">
                        <h2>Transcript</h2>
                        <p>[MUSIC PLAYING]</p>
                        <p><b>NARRATOR:</b> In 1918, the Diplomatic Courier Service was established
                            to support the work of American diplomats by ensuring that classified
                            messages and materials were delivered safely and securely to U.S.
                            embassies and consulates around the world. Over the hundred year history
                            of the courier service this core mission has not changed, and remains
                            critical to the national security of the United States.</p>
                        <p>Before the onset of the jet age, this small group of couriers traveled
                            tens of thousands of miles per year, often spending months on the road.
                            Following World War II, relations between the United States and the
                            Soviet Union—once allies—were increasingly strained and grew into what
                            became known as the Cold War.</p>
                        <p>Even during these complicated times, a mutual respect for international
                            conventions on diplomatic relations meant that the couriers were among
                            the few still able to travel into the Soviet Union. Making the trip from
                            Helsinki into Moscow several times a week, they brought the diplomatic
                            pouch with classified correspondence from Washington, news from the
                            West, and even personal mail.</p>
                        <p>[MUSIC PLAYING]</p>
                        <p><b>MR. JAMES VERREOS:</b> Some of the more interesting and funny things
                            occurred, of course, especially on trips to Moscow. The Soviets were
                            right on your back. You were almost never six feet away from somebody
                            who was looking over your shoulder.</p>
                        <p>We served the Soviet Union by what we called a satellite office in
                            Helsinki.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. ERNEST HOHMAN:</b> But Helsinki is very unique, there’s no
                            question about it. You go there in the winter months and they have a
                            sign that says, welcome to Santa Claus land. And that’s where, in a
                            sense, you feel—a lot of ice and snow. But it’s a beautiful country.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. KENNETH COOPER:</b> Every time I had the Helsinki detail it was
                            always in December, January, or February. So I have probably a different
                            perspective on this than the guys who did it in June, July, and August.
                            But we had a lot of fun there in the meantime.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. PHILIP OLIVARES:</b> Well, that detail was about a month. But we
                            rotated on it, because I think there were about four or five of us in
                            the mill on that. One man was traveling from Frankfurt by train up to
                            Hamburg. From Hamburg they flew to Copenhagen, and then continued on to
                            Stockholm, and then into Helsinki. And two guys would take it from
                            Helsinki into Leningrad and into Moscow.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. VERREOS:</b> We would station couriers in Helsinki for usually a
                            two month period. And during those two months, all they would do would
                            make the twice weekly trips into the Soviet Union with flights from
                            Helsinki to Leningrad to Moscow and back and out. And then once a month,
                            there was a train trip from Helsinki to Moscow delivering the
                            non-classified pouches. By treaty, nothing could come in as just plain
                            freight material, as you would say, commercial material.</p>
                        <p>Anything that went in for the embassy had to be in a pouch. So when we’re
                            moving furniture, for example, the non-classified pouch usually was one
                            or two freight cars. The material would be stuck into the freight car,
                            and the freight car would be closed, and a wire and lead seal and a tag
                            would be placed on that freight car as if it were a bag.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. DONOVAN KLINE:</b> On Helsinki detail, there were four couriers at
                            a time, up there rotating. Once a month, we went to Moscow on a Russian
                            a sleeper train out of Helsinki Station. We went to Viborg, and we
                            passed through there with little or no problems at all. It was nighttime
                            when we left—of course, saw nothing. It was pitch black. We would take
                            in surface pouches with copies of Newsweek and Time.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. VERREOS:</b> We were traveling soft class, because the class
                            conscious Soviets didn’t have anything like first class and second
                            class. They had soft class and hard class. Well, we were traveling soft
                            class, so we would have a cabin. All we did was play cards and enjoy
                            whatever food they had on the train. It wasn’t particularly what you’d
                            call first class, but it was better than hard class, believe me.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. COOPER:</b> I think we had one train trip a month. We flew in and
                            out most of the time, on a Russian Ilyushin 12 and then later an
                            Ilyushin 14 airplane. That was always kind of exciting. I remember one
                            instance where I had something like 12 large bags, all under diplomatic
                            seal. And we took up the whole center of the airplane. And I thought,
                            surely Russian customs are going to dig in their heels on this. But they
                            didn’t bat an eye.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. KLINE:</b> The other trips were always flying in. And we flew in
                            mostly on Aeroflot and FinnAir, depending on the day of the week, I
                            think.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. OLIVARES:</b> First time I flew a Saab, that was a funny
                            experience. Looked like a DC-3 with a nose wheel. The stewardess would
                            come and ask you, “Have you ever been on the Saab before?” And if you
                            hadn’t, they’d give you a little booklet. They said, “Please do not be
                            alarmed. When we land the pilot will feather the props to reverse the
                            engines to slow down to assist on the braking.”</p>
                        <p>But on doing so, a whole sheet of flame would come out of the exhaust
                            things. Blue flame would go past, I mean you could see this. People, I
                            remember seeing—I was pre-warned by the little booklet, but there was
                            some guy who didn’t read English and didn’t know this, and he jumped out
                            of his seat.</p>
                        <p>They were funny, those flights. I remember on one of the Aeroflots,
                            looking for my seatbelt. And the pilot happened to be coming on board.
                            He was going down the aisle. He said, “No, don’t worry about that. You
                            don’t need those.”</p>
                        <p>We used to get these caviar sandwiches for breakfast. It was a soft roll
                            with fresh caviar, not the tinned stuff. They took it for granted.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. VERREOS:</b> Going to Moscow in those days—to get off the train
                            and walk around the city was just depressive. The Russians were, the
                            people were hungry to hear about America. A few of them would speak some
                            English. A few of them spoke some German. Unfortunately, none of our
                            couriers that I knew of spoke Russki—[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]. But whenever we
                            were able to communicate, they were very, very friendly, the Russian
                            people.</p>
                        <p>Some KGB person was watching us. They knew that. And on a couple
                            occasions, people at a party that had one or two vodkas too many would
                            just flip the finger, knowing that the KGB would get it. Some were
                            defiant, but there were very few.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. OLIVARES:</b> Going into Moscow, it was a little difficult.
                            Everything was black, brown. Nobody had any color on them at all. The
                            city was so drab. It seems to me, most of my time in Moscow had to be in
                            the wintertime. There was always snow on the streets, people shoveling
                            it away, and everybody doing their duty. They just went about their life
                            like a drudgery. There was no happiness or pleasure in their faces.
                            Particularly when you got on the metro, which was very elaborate. The
                            government decided this is going to be our showpiece, and it was. It was
                            such a contrast with the people sitting in the metro.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. KLINE:</b> First trip there, I was surprised by how wide the
                            streets were there. They were really wide. There was more traffic there
                            than I expected to see. A good bit of it was Russian trucks, but there
                            were more cars than I ever expected to see. And we can go anywhere we
                            wanted around town. I walked a long ways there, up to Red Square one
                            day. Saw the mausoleum where the two stiffs were, Lenin and Stalin.</p>
                        <p>It was interesting. People were lined up eight abreast outside to get in.
                            When we got in, it was below ground. They had selective lighting with
                            these mummies were. They looked very lifelike, both of them. Stalin was
                            somewhat shorter than I expected. He was only about 5'3" or 4". Lenin
                            looked exactly like all the pictures I’d ever seen of him—goatee, the
                            whole thing. And he looked very natural.</p>
                        <p>We were respectful. I wasn’t sad at all. The others were, because that’s
                            why they were there. This was all they knew. This was their life since
                            1917, and this was 1957—40 year anniversary that year. It was
                            interesting, to say the least.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. HOHMAN:</b> We had this “propisk” which allowed us to jump the
                            line and get into the mausoleum to see Lenin and Stalin. Russians from
                            outside of Moscow were allowed at least once a year to come to Moscow on
                            their internal passport. And there were huge lines in all kinds of
                            weather. One of the hotels that we had was near Red Square. And after
                            dinner I walked over to where the mausoleum is for Lenin and Stalin, and
                            watched the changing of the guard.</p>
                        <p>And as I was watching, a man nudged up to me and said, “You American?”
                            Yeah. He said, “That’s a nice coat you’re wearing.” He said, “You want
                            to sell it to me?” I said, “No, it’s the only coat I’ve got.” He said,
                            “Do you have any jeans?” I said, “Look, this is a sacred place. We’re
                            right here for the changing of the guard. We’re in front of the
                            mausoleum for Lenin and Stalin, and you want to do this?” He says, “Why
                            not? What better place?” No, I didn’t sell them anything or give him
                            anything. But I was really shocked about that situation, really. Yeah. I
                            said, well, free enterprise. We’ve got it right here.</p>
                        <p>But the whole Kremlin, we were allowed to see the museum and so on. And
                            then across the way they had the GUM department store.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. COOPER:</b> We got to go into the Kremlin at one time on some kind
                            of an embassy tour. It was an unusual happening. We were shown a typical
                            dining room in the Tsar’s palace. I think they wanted to impress us on
                            how high on the hog the nobility lived as opposed to the peasants.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. KLINE:</b> There weren’t that many tourists in Moscow in those
                            days, outsiders. I went through St. Basil’s Cathedral on Red Square,
                            which I found fascinating for several things. There were no church
                            services being held in there, but it was quite pretty inside besides
                            being beautiful outside. There was a store there called GUM, G-U-M. I
                            don’t know what it stood for in Russian. I bought caviar there and
                            hauled the caviar out to Helsinki where we had parties with it. And it
                            was delicious beluga caviar, really delightful.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. COOPER:</b> I did get to go to GUM, the big department store, one
                            time. Sort of an exercise in futility. Huge lines at every counter.
                            There was a shortage of everything.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. HOHMAN:</b> The huge department store was a depressing sort of
                            place. There were only limited things that we could really find of
                            interest, even though we had a good exchange rate. Musical instruments
                            were rather cheap, or some books—English books, because they didn’t
                            recognize the copyrights. One of the interesting things was Russian
                            caviar. The caviar was from virgin sturgeon, they said. That was the
                            best tasting. There really wasn’t a heck of a lot to buy.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. VERREOS:</b> In the men’s shoe department they had four sizes of
                            shoes, and two colors—black and brown. Apparently they bought the size a
                            little bigger so they could stuff paper or whatever in so that the shoe
                            would fit. In 90% of the different stands, say in the women’s department
                            for dresses or stockings and stuff like that, they would have on
                            display. But they would have no product available to sell.</p>
                        <p>You’d go down the big street on which the embassy was, to the various
                            shops. You’d go to the shop that sold bread. And you look in there, and
                            there is no bread. But there’d be a line of people going around the
                            block. It was very depressing to see people there.</p>
                        <p>The pricing situation was ridiculous. We could get seats to the Bolshoi
                            in the first eight rows for what it cost you to buy an egg if there was
                            one available in the market. I remember, it was 32 rubles for the seats
                            at the Bolshoi, and it’s 32 or 34 rubles to buy an egg.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. CELLA:</b> We spent the afternoon walking around Red Square. We’d
                            always get tickets to go to the Bolshoi and Stanislavsky. I remember
                            coming out of an intermission at the Bolshoi. I guess we were watching
                            some big ballet. The best seats are the first row of that center
                            balcony. And right in the first row of that sitting up above us was
                            Khrushchev and Bulganin. Bulganin was the official head, and Khrushchev
                            was the chairman. We were that close to them. The balcony is only like,
                            that high from the ceiling of this room.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. HOHMAN:</b> There is a great amusement area, Gorky Park. Very
                            nice, with the Ferris wheel that they had there. It was a fun place. A
                            lot of people with their children there, also. They had games, swings
                            and so on, for them. Chess was a big game. Of course there were very
                            skilled individuals using all these well-known moves, and then people
                            surrounding these chess players, watching them. And they’re going, “Ooh,
                            aah.”</p>
                        <p>It was light and fun. Moscow generally, because of the lighting and
                            because of the atmospheric conditions, the way the buildings weren’t
                            properly maintained, had a drab atmosphere to it. This was a ray of
                            sunshine, particularly during the spring and summer months.</p>
                        <p>And a favorite among them was eating ice cream. Because I understand
                            Micoyan, one of the Russian premiers, visited the United States and he
                            liked ice cream. He brought ice cream machines back to Russia. And
                            Russians, even you got four or five feet of snow out there, eating a
                            cone of ice cream.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. CELLA:</b> We used to stay in that place called the Amerikanski
                            Dom, the American House, a good distance walk from the embassy.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. OLIVARES:</b> That was a way from the embassy itself. It was about
                            a mile down the road. There was a building with mostly the military air
                            attache people, the staff, the sergeants and all that. But that was a
                            big center of life for the Americans. That was—everybody, even the staff
                            from the embassy went down there. And there was mostly bachelors in
                            there.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. VERREOS:</b> Over at Amerikanski Dom, the America House, which was
                            about two, three miles away from the embassy, and it was on the Moscow
                            River pretty much opposite the entry to Gorky Park. And Amerikanski Dom
                            is where the single personnel lived. The girls that were so-called maids
                            to do the cleaning service and the maids in the cafeteria in Amerikanski
                            Dom were all striking beauties, believe me.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. KLINE:</b> In the America House, Amerikanski Dome, we had two or
                            three Russian women who served our meals at the restaurant there. One
                            was called Tanya. And she spoke very good English. And her ears were
                            wide open at all times, listening to the conversations around those
                            tables. And we’d walk in and we’d say, “Do svidaniya, Tanya.”</p>
                        <p><b>MR. CELLA:</b> In the Amerikanski Dom was a nice looking woman who
                            worked there as a waitress and everything. Tanya, her name was. So I
                            made a big spiel to her. And all she said was, her response was, “You
                            want soup?” That’s all I heard after that. “Vince, do you want
                            soup?”</p>
                        <p><b>MR. HOHMAN:</b> We stayed initially at that time at the so-called
                            Amerikanski Dom, which was a housing area separate from the embassy, but
                            it was an embassy place. We had food there that was served by a Russian,
                            a very, very interesting woman. And some of the fellas tried to date her
                            and so on, and she would never budge and say, “Soup? Vince, soup? More
                            soup for you?”</p>
                        <p><b>MR. VERREOS:</b> The Amerikanski Dome, by the way, was the social
                            center for all of the diplomatic personnel in Moscow. Every night at
                            Amerikanski Dom we were showing some American movie. So we always had a
                            lot of the diplomatic corps would be coming in to see the movie.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. KLINE:</b> Once a week they held open house there for the Western
                            foreign embassies—Brits, the Swedes, the Finns, whoever, you know,
                            Germans, for bingo. One night there was a terrible noise out on the side
                            of this building toward the Moscow River. And we all looked out and here
                            it was, the Russians practicing for their Independence Day
                            celebration—so-called Independence Day celebration—in November, on the
                            anniversary of the Russian Revolution.</p>
                        <p>They rolled tanks by us. They rolled cars by us. They rolled great big
                            huge guns on flatbed trucks, and all kinds of stuff, making this
                            clamorous noise for a couple of hours, practicing for the spontaneous
                            demonstration that was going to be two weeks later in Red Square.</p>
                        <p>[MUSIC PLAYING]</p>
                        <p>Later on when we lost our space in Amerikanski Dom, we stayed in Russian
                            hotels. And there were women overseers on each of the floors. I’m sure
                            they kept sure that we didn’t go anyplace. Or if they did, they called
                            somebody. I’m sure of that. I don’t think—well, I don’t know, but I
                            don’t think I was followed up there. I may have been, who knows?</p>
                        <p>I didn’t worry about it. They didn’t want an incident and we didn’t want
                            one. They wanted their couriers outside treated well, and so they
                            treated us. Now, I don’t know whether they followed us or not. They
                            probably did, but I wasn’t looking for it and I wasn’t worried about it
                            ’cause I wasn’t doing anything wrong.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. OLIVARES:</b> Well, we knew in Moscow, definitely. I don’t know
                            about the other countries behind the Curtain, but definitely in Russia
                            you knew somebody was following you. Yeah. Wherever you went, somebody
                            kept an eye on you. Because you stood out too, in those days. Your
                            dress, for one thing. Nobody bothered you, of course. Most of them were
                            rather surprised to meet an American. It was a far off place they’d
                            heard of, but—Oh, Americans here?</p>
                        <p>They couldn’t believe it. If you were a foreigner, they thought you were
                            from the of their own satellite countries. They’d look at you and say,
                            [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]—in their own language. And you say, No, Amerikanski.
                            They couldn’t believe it. Those people? As much as we would say on this
                            side, Russians? Communists here in New York?</p>
                        <p>Your job was to take care of those pouches. But I don’t think we ever
                            felt that somebody was threatening us or trying to steal them, but we
                            always have to assume that. And that’s why you took care of them.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. HOHMAN:</b> I know sometimes as a newcomer, we were tailed by the
                            KGB and so on. They were all very curious as to what you were doing.
                            They figured that you were more than just a diplomatic courier.
                            Occasionally you were able to speak to some Russians, but it was very
                            difficult to do so.</p>
                        <p>I had an incident also, coming out of a hotel in Moscow where a young
                            fellow got a hold of me, and he spoke English quite well. And it turns
                            out that he was born in Brooklyn, New York. And I, having been born in
                            New York, I was familiar with the area where he was located. And he said
                            that as a teenager his father picked up the family and went to
                            Russia.</p>
                        <p>They were originally from Russia, the family. And there was this call out
                            —Come back to Mother Russia and rebuild the country. You have your
                            obligation, even though you’re an overseas Russian, and so on. So he did
                            that, and took his entire family.</p>
                        <p>This young fellow that I was talking to, he lived outside of the city of
                            Moscow. But he said that they had the authority, they had to have
                            internal passports and it gave the authority that at least once a year
                            he could come to Moscow and he could be able to see the Lenin-Stalin
                            mausoleum and so on, and other sites and places there. So he asked me if
                            I would do a favor for him. And I said, “What’s the favor?” He says,
                            “Help me get into the American Embassy.”</p>
                        <p>I said, “Well, just walk into it.” He says, “No. There are militia guards
                            out there and they would restrain me from coming in.” He said, “I’m
                            trying to get back to the United States. I don’t like this country. They
                            regard me as a traitor. I hardly speak Russian. And so speaking, I feel
                            I’m an American from Brooklyn.” And he had a Brooklyn-ese type accent,
                            too. Which surprised me, that he wasn’t able to get into the embassy. He
                            said, “No, no. Militia guards won’t let me go in there. And he said,
                            I’ve tried a couple of times and they stopped me.” And I said, “Well,
                            I’m sorry. I can’t help you either.”</p>
                        <p>So, whether a case of entrapment or so on, I don’t know. A very
                            sympathetic sort of arrangement too, that he didn’t have access to go
                            back to the place of his birth. Because it’s part of our basic nature to
                            help others, even though they are strangers.</p>
                        <p><b>MR. CELLA:</b> But it was fun, Moscow. You’d try to enjoy it, because
                            we were in there a lot. I couldn’t wait to get back to Helsinki. That’s
                            another thing. On a train, the difference—how you notice when you cross
                            the border into Russia. There was just unending ending trees, roads with
                            nobody on them. But then you’d come back and then cross the border into
                            Finland—nice little houses with the smoke coming out of the chimneys.
                            Everything nice and clean. Huge, huge difference.</p>
                        <p>[MUSIC PLAYING]</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <aside class="hsg-width-one-third">
                <div id="sections" class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Department History</h2>
                    </div>
                    <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/timeline">Administrative Timeline of the
                                Department of State</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/buildings">Buildings of the
                                Department</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people">People</a>
                            <ul>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/secretaries">Biographies
                                        of the Secretaries of State</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/principals-chiefs"
                                        >Principal Officers and Chiefs of Mission</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels">Travels</a>
                            <ul>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels/secretary">Travels of
                                        the Secretary</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels/president">Travels of
                                        the President</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/visits">Visits by Foreign Leaders</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/wwi">World War I and the Department</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/diplomatic-couriers" class="highlight"
                                >U.S. Diplomatic Couriers</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </aside>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
