<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div data-template="pages:load">
        <div id="static-title" class="hidden">Through the Khyber Pass - U.S. Diplomatic Couriers -
            Department History</div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
                <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app">Home</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory">Department History</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory/diplomatic-couriers">U.S. Diplomatic
                            Couriers</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory/diplomatic-couriers/through-the-khyber-pass"
                            >Through the Khyber Pass</a>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds">
                <div id="content-inner" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <h1>U.S. Diplomatic Couriers: Through the Khyber Pass</h1>
                    <!-- Start of Brightcove Player -->
                    <div style="position: relative; display: block;">
                        <div style="padding-top: 56.25%;">
                            <video data-video-id="4262345725001" data-account="1705665025"
                                data-player="HJ8lQG1Eg" data-embed="default"
                                data-application-id="data-application-id" class="video-js"
                                controls="controls"
                                style="position: absolute; top: 0px; right: 0px; bottom: 0px; left: 0px; width: 100%; height: 100%;"/>
                            <script
                                src="https://players.brightcove.net/1705665025/HJ8lQG1Eg_default/index.min.js"
                            />
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <!-- End of Brightcove Player -->
                    <div id="synopsis">
                        <h2>Synopsis</h2>
                        <p>In order to reach the U.S. Embassy in Afghanistan, the Diplomatic
                            Couriers traveled by car through the Khyber Pass. This short documentary
                            tells the story of the journey from Karachi, Pakistan, to Kabul,
                            Afghanistan, with words and images from the Diplomatic Couriers and
                            staff of that era.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div id="more-information">
                        <h2>More information</h2>
                        <dl>
                            <dt>Released</dt>
                            <dd>2016</dd>
                            <dt>Length</dt>
                            <dd>18:02</dd>
                            <dt>Creator</dt>
                            <dd>Rebecca A. Ross, Foreign Service Officer, U.S. Department of
                                State</dd>
                        </dl>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <h2 id="transcript">Transcript</h2>
                        <p><b>MS ROSS:</b> In 1918, the Diplomatic Courier Service was established
                            to support the work of American diplomats by ensuring that classified
                            messages and materials were delivered safely and securely to U.S.
                            embassies and consulates around the world. In the 1950s, before the
                            onset of the jet age, this small group of couriers traveled tens of
                            thousands of miles per year, often spending months on the road. One of
                            the trips they made was from Pakistan to Afghanistan through the Khyber
                            Pass.</p>
                        <p><b>MR VERREOS:</b> The most interesting travel that I had was while I was
                            in Manila and detailed to Karachi, which at that time was the capital of
                            Pakistan, and Karachi is where we served Afghanistan.</p>
                        <p><b>MR COOPER:</b> Well, many couriers would agree with me that it was one
                            of the most exciting trips we were taking at that time—just the mere
                            fact that it was over the Khyber Pass.</p>
                        <p><b>MR HOHMAN:</b> The Khyber Pass was an exciting, interesting,
                            unsettling sort of a trip.</p>
                        <p><b>MR COOPER:</b> At that time, we had a trunk route that went from
                            Manila to Paris. I’d fly out to Karachi, making the usual stops on the
                            way, and instead of continuing on to Paris, I would relieve a courier on
                            the Karachi detail. He would continue on to Paris, and I would stay
                            there for two months until I was relieved.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN:</b> And the trip left Manila to Bangkok, Bangkok to Karachi.
                            And then Karachi then down to Ceylon, which is Sri Lanka now. And then
                            they would come back to Karachi, then they would head north to Peshawar
                            and then by car through the Khyber.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DIECKMAN:</b> So we went from Hong Kong to Singapore, and I think I
                            must have travelled then from Singapore to New Delhi, and from there
                            taken a train to Peshawar, where I was to meet a courier in Peshawar for
                            the rest of the trip to Kabul, which I didn’t know how that was all
                            going to happen but I was assured that it was very easy and very
                            interesting—(laughter)—and I would love it.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN: </b>During my tour, they always went by car, and there were
                            always—there was always danger: flashfloods and bandits.</p>
                        <p><b>MR HOHMAN:</b> The political circumstances were such that the air link
                            had broken. We were using land transport. In an embassy, you’d have a
                            carry-all vehicle to go through the Khyber Pass.</p>
                        <p><b>MR VERREOS:</b> We would take the train from Karachi to Peshawar,
                            overnight at the Dean’s Hotel, and the embassy in Kabul would send down
                            their vehicle and driver who would meet us and pick us up in the morning
                            —the next morning. And then from Peshawar, we would go through the
                            Khyber Pass to go into Afghanistan.</p>
                        <p><b>MR COOPER:</b> We traveled alone with an Afghan driver. We had two
                            drivers I recall particularly, Abdul Ainan (ph) and Abdul Adjan (ph).
                            Most of the time, we made it pretty much nonstop—first over the Khyber
                            Pass and then over the Hindu Kush into Kabul.</p>
                        <p><b>MR VERREOS:</b> The embassy had a specially built Ford. By using the
                            motor of the car as a power source, they had lathes and welding
                            apparatus to repair the axles that would be broken on the trip up to
                            Kabul.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN:</b> And my driver was Abdul, an Afghan, and he’d brought the
                            courier down from—the courier down from Kabul and dropped him off that
                            morning. I almost fainted when he came in; it was Jim Verreos. “What are
                            you doing here?” Then we started up, and dirt sides of the roads,
                            camels, and trucks coming down with the bodies hanging on with their
                            robes flapping in the wind. There’s not much greenery at all. If there
                            was pavement, it’s covered with dirt. And then it just—and it kind of
                            just goes over to the side, and it’s all just dirt. You could slide
                            off.</p>
                        <p><b>MR HOHMAN:</b> Going through the Khyber Pass, and there really wasn’t
                            much space. It was a relatively narrow road. It was two-way traffic, but
                            it was close two-way traffic, winding through upwards and of course
                            downward.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DIECKMAN:</b> The road was bumpy and dusty. And I looked to the
                            right as we were driving along, and oh, my gosh, we were thousands of
                            feet above any ground down there. And I thought, ooh, there’s no
                            barricade or fence or lines in the road or anything. We just had to
                            count on the driver. Well, he did this for a living, so we hoped that he
                            remembered how to do it all. The mountains were absolutely wonderful.
                            They were so high and so beautiful.</p>
                        <p><b>MR COOPER:</b> On the—interesting: On the side of the road—I don’t
                            know what kind of stone it is, probably granite—they had carved the
                            crests of all the various British regiments that had served in this fort
                            over the years, and their regimental crests were all carved on the stone
                            along there. It was very interesting to see. The fort itself was up much
                            higher.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN:</b> And of course, the Khyber Rifles up at the top.
                            There—this was their armory or stronghold up on the—up at the top and
                            that’s where they were stationed. It was something to see that you read
                            about.</p>
                        <p><b>MR VERREOS:</b> You got to this high point where the Pakistanis had
                            set up their border control station, then you would show your exit
                            papers to exit Pakistan, and it was a little wooden shack and there was
                            one telephone pole. I’d say about 20 yards in front of that shack—this
                            is really nice to look at—there was two posts and a wire fence and a
                            gate, but on the other side there was nothing there. And you could walk
                            around it, but they’d put that fence up, and this was the entry into
                            Afghanistan. And I inquired. I said, “What’s this telephone pole doing
                            here?” And they had in that Afghan office, they had a bunch of people
                            down there writing down messages. That was the one phone line from Kabul
                            to the border, but you couldn’t make a telephone call outside the
                            country. You could call and send your message to the station there at
                            the Pakistan-Kabul border, they would write it down, walk it across the
                            border, put the money in, and they would then telephone New York or
                            London or wherever they wanted to telephone, and pass the message
                            on.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN:</b> So we start up and we get to the border, and I can’t get
                            in. “Your visa has expired.” So Abdul said, “All right, no problem.
                            We’ll start back.” Well, he’s careening down the Khyber back to the
                            consulate in Peshawar, the Afghan consulate. We got there just before 12
                            o’clock, they stamped my passport, and then I said, “Is there a ladies’
                            room here?” And he says, “What’s a ladies’ room?” Well, then I had to go
                            back to the staff house, scared them, and then we took off again.
                            Anyway, we get through the Khyber, get through the border, and he
                            says—Abdul says, “Notice the nice, smooth roads we have here in
                            Afghanistan.” Well, a lot better than the dirt roads in the Khyber.</p>
                        <p><b>MR VERREOS:</b> There was no paved road inside the Afghan side. A few
                            hundred yards off, you could see the Kabul River, and it was green for
                            about a hundred yards off of the river on each side, and after that was
                            desert—rocky. In the far distance you could see the Hindu Kush
                            Mountains, and we were headed toward those Hindu Kush Mountains, roughly
                            following a course that followed the Kabul River. And my driver told me
                            this was the regular caravan route, and he said, “It’s easy to follow,”
                            and I said, “How come?” He said, “Well, I’ll try to point them out to
                            you.” At different points along it there would be a small pile of rocks
                            on this side and on that side, and your road was in between those.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DIECKMAN:</b> And I was looking around for the road, and I didn’t
                            see one, and so I asked. I said, “Where—what road are we taking?” And
                            they said, “Road?” (Laughter.) But the driver apparently knew his way
                            because we did get to Kabul.</p>
                        <p><b>MR VERREOS:</b> On several trips, I encountered caravans, camel
                            caravans coming or going along that route. On one of my trips, I got
                            trapped. We were going through the Kabul River gorge, and there had been
                            a tremendous rainstorm or something and there had been a washout of the
                            road. And we came up to it; there were a whole bunch of camels and what
                            have you in front, and the driver stopped. There was a small, about
                            two-foot—two, three-foot wide section of the mountainside, and people
                            could pass on foot. And I sent my driver up to see if he could negotiate
                            with any cars that were trying to come this way that couldn’t come. We
                            would trade—the occupants of the car that was, say, southbound would use
                            the embassy car to go to down to Peshawar, and the courier—myself —could
                            use his car to go up to Kabul. And he said there were two cars on the
                            other side and none of them agreed to that. There was no sense in
                            staying there. I asked him, “Is there any other way to get to Kabul?”
                            And the driver said yes, there was. So I said, “Well, let’s try
                            that.”</p>
                        <p>So—and then we backed out of there, and it was hard because we had to
                            move camels and what have you, and donkeys, in order to back out of that
                            narrow part of the gorge. And once we got out of the narrow part he took
                            off and found some small town on the side. Fortunately, the driver, who
                            was Pakistani, spoke Afghan. He got me accommodations in a—at a vacant
                            wooden shack, no bed or anything, just a wooden floor.</p>
                        <p>The next morning we took off and we drove—finally got into Kabul.
                            Meanwhile, Kabul had sent somebody down the regular road to find me, who
                            reported he couldn’t find me and he reported back by radio. And finally,
                            when I got up there they were a little pissed that I had moved instead
                            of stayed there and waited for help. But you have to—my concern: I had
                            the pouches; I’m not going to sit on a river gorge there hoping somebody
                            might come. I felt it was my duty—just common sense. I was either going
                            to go back to Peshawar or up to Kabul. And since my driver said there
                            was a second way to Kabul, I preferred to take the second road to Kabul
                            and accomplish my mission, which I did. But like I said, it was kind of
                            a small adventure.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN:</b> And then we were going to start up the gorge, and we
                            started out, and up, up, up, up, and the canyons—it’s just so deep. And
                            there was a truck coming around the corner with more flapping robes, and
                            he wants to know do I want to take a picture. Oh, no, no. (Laughter.)
                            Oh, that was the scariest, scariest ride I ever had.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DIECKMAN:</b> So we got to Kabul, and Kabul was a very busy place
                            because we landed right about where the market was, which was very, very
                            busy with a lot of people going up and down and around and about, and
                            carrying things and buying things.</p>
                        <p><b>MR COOPER:</b> Well, it could hardly be much more primitive. I
                            remember all of the roofs of the houses, the roofs were made of mud. You
                            got too much rain, you were in trouble. And I think I was told that
                            there were only two buildings in Kabul that had corrugated tin roofs,
                            and one of them was the American embassy, and I forget what the other
                            one was.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DIECKMAN:</b> The one thing I really noticed is that the women had
                            so much cloth on. It went down to the floor and covered a lot of their
                            head and all of their body, and it’s what you really noticed, it’s there
                            is a woman in there. (Laughter.)</p>
                        <p><b>MR HOHMAN:</b> I wandered around a little bit between the time we were
                            ready to set off for the run to Jalalabad, but they told me not to
                            wander around too much in the streets because people had a tendency to
                            disappear. It was still a rough country.</p>
                        <p>What was rather interesting is the various clothing that the Afghans were
                            wearing, and quite often you’d see castoff American uniforms from the
                            Second World War—coats, raincoats that they had; sometimes you’d see
                            somebody wearing an Eisenhower jacket over a long, flowing robe.</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN:</b> I was there a week. I thought it was very nice. We played
                            golf—nine holes. The ball, you’d hit it and it’d hit a rock and then it
                            would ricochet, and there was deep, deep grass. I don’t know how the
                            caddies ever found the ball. Just to say we played golf in Kabul.</p>
                        <p><b>MR COOPER:</b> We decided to climb up the mountain to where they have
                            a cannon mounted. There was an old boy that used to fire that cannon off
                            at noon every day. He was very proud of this gold watch that he would
                            produce, and he’d mark it down and wait till noon, and then he’d light
                            the fuse on the cannon, then it would go off. So I didn’t know how
                            accurate his watch was. (Laughter.) Well, it pretty much established
                            noon in Kabul. We called it “Kabul boom time.” (Laughter.)</p>
                        <p><b>MS DUNN:</b> And even when I was there in '73, we stopped at a—along
                            the Khyber, we stopped at a stronghold of some type, and the guy came
                            out and he had bandoliers across his chest and a big rifle. And I
                            thought, “Well, then not much has changed.”</p>
                        <p><b>MR VERREOS:</b> Believe me, like I said, that was about the most
                            interesting trip in the world.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <aside class="hsg-width-one-third">
                <div id="sections" class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Department History</h2>
                    </div>
                    <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/timeline">Administrative Timeline of the
                                Department of State</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/buildings">Buildings of the
                                Department</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people">People</a>
                            <ul>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/secretaries">Biographies
                                        of the Secretaries of State</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/principals-chiefs"
                                        >Principal Officers and Chiefs of Mission</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels">Travels</a>
                            <ul>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels/secretary">Travels of
                                        the Secretary</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels/president">Travels of
                                        the President</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/visits">Visits by Foreign Leaders</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/wwi">World War I and the Department</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/diplomatic-couriers" class="highlight"
                                >U.S. Diplomatic Couriers</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </aside>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
