<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div id="static-title" class="hidden">Tips - Search</div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
            <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                <li>
                    <a href="$app">Home</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="$app/search">Search</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="$app/search/tips">Search Tips</a>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <aside id="contents" class="hsg-width-one-third">
            <div class="hsg-panel">
                <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                    <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Contents</h2>
                </div>
                <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="#defaults">Defaults</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="#scope">Scope</a>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="#keywords">Searching with Keywords</a>
                        <ul>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#phrases">Phrases</a>
                            </li>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#booleans">Booleans</a>
                            </li>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#wildcards">Wildcards</a>
                            </li>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#proximity">Proximity</a>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="#dates-filter">Filtering by Date and Time</a>
                        <ul>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#exact-date">Exact Date</a>
                            </li>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#exact-date-time">Exact Date and Time</a>
                            </li>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#date-range">Date Range</a>
                            </li>
                            <ul>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="#month-year">Month-Year</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="#single-year">Single Year</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="#year-range">Year Range</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                            <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                <a href="#date-time-range">Date and Time Range</a>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                        <a href="#volumes-filter">Filtering by Volume</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </div>
        </aside>
        <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds" data-template="app:fix-links">
            <div id="content-inner">
                <h1>Search Tips</h1>
                <p>The Office of the Historian’s <a href="$app/search">search engine</a> contains
                    several useful search options. Understanding the search engine’s defaults, as
                    well as the following techniques and syntax, will help improve your search
                    results. Example searches linked below will pre-fill the search form with the
                    parameters of your search to see the results.</p>
                <div id="defaults">
                    <h2>Defaults</h2>
                    <ul>
                        <li>By default, the search engine returns documents from the entire
                                site<sup>†</sup> containing <strong>all</strong> of the search terms
                            you enter. (Note: Before December 2017, the search engine’s default
                            behavior was to return documents containing <strong>any</strong> of the
                            terms. To perform that kind of search now, just place an <a
                                href="#booleans">OR</a> boolean operator between each term.)</li>
                        <li>All keyword searches are <strong>case-insensitive</strong>, so searching
                            for “SALT” will return the same results as searching for “salt.”</li>
                        <li>You can refine a query by: <ol>
                                <li>narrowing its scope to specific sections of the website;</li>
                                <li>using phrase, boolean, wildcard, and proximity operators in your
                                    keyword search; and</li>
                                <li>filtering results by date and time ranges or specific
                                        <em>Foreign Relations</em> volumes.</li>
                            </ol></li>
                    </ul>
                    <p><sup>†</sup> Note that the search engine’s results are limited to the
                        materials that the Office of the Historian has digitized. Please consult the
                        full list of <em>Foreign Relations</em> volumes <a
                            href="$app/historicaldocuments">by administration</a> to see which
                        volumes have been digitized (indicated by the phrase, “full text,” next to
                        each volume’s title). For early <em>FRUS</em> volumes not yet available
                        here, we provide links to the <a
                            href="https://uwdc.library.wisc.edu/collections/FRUS/">University of
                            Wisconsin Madison <em>FRUS</em> collection</a>, or in some
                        circumstances, WorldCat.</p>
                </div>
                <div id="scope">
                    <h2>Scope</h2>
                    <p>Beneath the keyword search field is a set of checkboxes, labeled “Filter by
                        Section.” Selecting any of the checkboxes can narrow the scope of your
                        search to specific sections of the website, resulting in a faster, more
                        specific query. The default set of checkboxes contains the major content
                        sections of the website:<br/>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Historical Documents <ul><li>Includes <em>Foreign Relations of the
                                            United States</em> documents</li></ul></li>
                            <li>Department History <ul><li>Includes Principal Officers and Chiefs of
                                        Mission, Travels of the President and Secretary, Visits of
                                        Foreign Leaders, etc.</li></ul></li>
                            <li>Countries <ul><li>Includes Guide to the United States’ History of
                                        Recognition, Diplomatic, and Consular Relations, by Country,
                                        since 1776</li></ul></li>
                            <li>Conferences <ul><li>Includes Transcripts of conferences held by the
                                        Office of the Historian</li></ul></li>
                            <li>History of the <em>Foreign Relations</em> Series</li>
                            <li>About <ul><li>Includes FAQ, Advisory Committee
                                Minutes</li></ul></li>
                            <li>Retired Resources <ul><li>Includes Milestones,
                                Education</li></ul></li>
                        </ul>
                    </p>
                    <p>To search for articles about U.S. diplomatic history that relate to peace,
                        you could select these two sections and enter the keyword “peace”:</p>
                    <blockquote> ☑ Department History<br/> ☑ Retired Resources (Milestones)<br/>
                        <hr/>
                        <a
                            href="$app/search?q=peace&amp;within=department&amp;within=retired&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                            >peace</a></blockquote>
                    <p>(Click on the link to try out this search.)</p>
                    <p>If no scope checkboxes are selected, the entire site will be searched. To
                        achieve the best results, combine scope with the following keyword search
                        operators:</p>
                </div>
                <div id="keywords">
                    <h2>Searching with Keywords</h2>
                    <div id="phrases">
                        <h3>Phrases</h3>
                        <p>When you type your search terms into the box, the search engine will
                            search for those terms, individually, anywhere in a document. To force
                            the search engine to find fixed phrases (i.e., specific, ordered
                            combinations of words), place the phrase in quotation marks. To locate
                            documents which include both “peaceful” and “nuclear” anywhere in the
                            text, use the following search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=peaceful+nuclear&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >peaceful nuclear</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>To locate documents which use the phrase “peaceful nuclear,” use this
                            search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=%22peaceful+nuclear%22&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >"peaceful nuclear"</a>
                        </blockquote>
                    </div>
                    <div id="booleans">
                        <h3>Booleans</h3>
                        <p>The search engine will allow you to perform Boolean searches (AND, OR,
                            and NOT). Boolean operators must be in all caps.</p>
                        <p>You can use Boolean operators with individual terms or with phrases
                            enclosed in quotation marks. For example, to locate documents which
                            include both the word “Kissinger” and the phrase “peaceful nuclear,” use
                            this search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=Kissinger+%22peaceful+nuclear%22&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >Kissinger "peaceful nuclear"</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>To locate documents which include either “Rhodesia” or “Zimbabwe,” use
                            this search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=Rhodesia+OR+Zimbabwe&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >Rhodesia OR Zimbabwe</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>To locate documents which include the phrase “arms control” but exclude
                            documents which also include the term “SALT,” use this search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=%22arms++control%22+NOT+SALT&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >"arms control" NOT SALT</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>You can also use the plus (+) and minus (-) signs to include or exclude
                            certain terms. To search for documents which must include the phrase
                            “law of the sea” and may include the term “seabed,” use this search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=%2B%22law+of+the+sea%22+seabed&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >+"law of the sea" seabed</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>To search for documents which include “Korea” but not “DMZ,” use this
                            search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=Korea+-DMZ&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >Korea -DMZ</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>Finally, you can use parentheses to nest your searches. To find documents
                            which include “Guatemala” or “El Salvador” and “Belize,” use this
                            search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=(Guatemala+OR+%22El+Salvador%22)+AND+Belize&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >(Guatemala OR "El Salvador") AND Belize</a>
                        </blockquote>
                    </div>
                    <div id="wildcards">
                        <h3>Wildcards</h3>
                        <p>If you are unsure about the spelling of a term or want to find variants
                            of a term, you can use wildcards. The search engine supports two
                            wildcard characters: ? and *.</p>
                        <p>If you want to replace a single letter in your search term, use ? in your
                            query. To find documents which include “text” or “test,” use this
                            search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=te%3Ft&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >te?t</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>Note that the above search will not return hits for “Tet” or “teapot.” If
                            you want to replace zero or more letters in your search term use * in
                            your query. For example, to find documents which include “Vietnam” and
                            “Vietnamese,” use this search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=Vietna*&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance*"
                                >Vietna*</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>Note that the above search will not return hits for “Viet Nam,” another
                            spelling of the same country. You may have to try multiple variants of
                            the same search to get all the results you need.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div id="proximity">
                        <h3>Proximity</h3>
                        <p>If you are searching for common words, you can tell the search engine to
                            only return documents in which the words are within a distance you
                            define. To find documents which include “Cuba” and “submarine” within 10
                            words of each other, use this search:</p>
                        <blockquote>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=%22Cuba+submarine%22~10&amp;within=entire-site&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >"Cuba submarine"~10</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <p>We are aware that “keyword in context” summary of the results of
                            proximity searches are not displaying correctly. The search results
                            themselves, however, are reliable.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div id="dates-filter">
                    <h2>Filtering By Date and Time (Alpha Release)</h2>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Date and time filters may be applied to searches within the Historical
                            Documents (<em>Foreign Relations</em> series) section of the site. These
                            filters will be active only if the Historical Documents section is
                            checked.</li>
                        <li>Exact dates or date-time ranges may be used in conjunction with keywords
                            and/or volumes, or used alone by leaving the search box blank.</li>
                        <li>Date and time filters may be used at the beginning of a search or to
                            refine the results of a search.</li>
                        <li>Per U.S. conventions, dates should be entered in Month-Date-Year format
                            and time in 12-hour format, with “am” or “pm” selected.</li>
                    </ul>

                    <div id="exact-date">
                        <h3>Exact Date</h3>
                        <p>To search or filter results by an exact date, enter a single date into
                            the “Start Date” set of fields. For example, a search for historical
                            documents dated December 7, 1941 should be entered as:</p>
                        <blockquote> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                            <hr/>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Month</th>
                                    <th>Day</th>
                                    <th>Year</th>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>12</td>
                                    <td>07</td>
                                    <td>1941</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <hr/>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1941-12-07&amp;sort-by=date-asc"
                                >live example</a>
                        </blockquote>
                    </div>
                    <div id="exact-date-time">
                        <h3>Exact Date and Time</h3>
                        <p>To search or filter results by an exact date and time, enter a single
                            date into the “Start Date” set of fields and a single time into the
                            “Start Time” set of fields. For example, a search for historical
                            documents created on December 7, 1941 at 8 p.m. should be entered
                            as:</p>
                        <blockquote> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                            <hr/>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Month</th>
                                    <th>Day</th>
                                    <th>Year</th>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>12</td>
                                    <td>07</td>
                                    <td>1941</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>Start Time</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Hour</th>
                                    <th>Minute</th>
                                    <th/>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>8</td>
                                    <td>00</td>
                                    <td>◦ am ⦿ pm</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <hr/>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1941-12-07&amp;start-time=20:00&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                >live example</a>
                        </blockquote>
                    </div>
                    <div id="date-range">
                        <h3>Date Range</h3>
                        <p>To search or filter results by a date range, use the “Start Date” and
                            “End Date” sets of fields. For example, a search for historical
                            documents including the term “Cuba” and created between October 16, 1962
                            and October 28, 1962 should be entered as:</p>
                        <blockquote> Cuba*<br/>
                            <hr/> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                            <hr/>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Month</th>
                                    <th>Day</th>
                                    <th>Year</th>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>10</td>
                                    <td>16</td>
                                    <td>1962</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <hr/>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>End Date</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Month</th>
                                    <th>Day</th>
                                    <th>Year</th>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>10</td>
                                    <td>28</td>
                                    <td>1962</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <hr/>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=Cuba*&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1962-10-16&amp;end-date=1962-10-28&amp;sort-by=date-asc"
                                >live example</a>
                        </blockquote>
                        <div id="month-year">
                            <h4>Month-Year</h4>
                            <p>To search or filter results for all historical documents produced on
                                any day during a particular month and year, use a date range search.
                                For example, a search for historical documents including the terms
                                “National Security Council” or “NSC” dated sometime in September
                                1974 should be entered as:</p>
                            <blockquote> "National Security Council" OR "NSC"<br/>
                                <hr/> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                                <hr/>
                                <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                    <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                                    <thead>
                                        <th>Month</th>
                                        <th>Day</th>
                                        <th>Year</th>
                                    </thead>
                                    <tr>
                                        <td>09</td>
                                        <td>01</td>
                                        <td>1974</td>
                                    </tr>
                                </table>
                                <hr/>
                                <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                    <caption><strong>End Date</strong></caption>
                                    <thead>
                                        <th>Month</th>
                                        <th>Day</th>
                                        <th>Year</th>
                                    </thead>
                                    <tr>
                                        <td>09</td>
                                        <td>30</td>
                                        <td>1974</td>
                                    </tr>
                                </table>
                                <hr/>
                                <a
                                    href="$app/search?q=%22National+Security+Council%22+OR+%22NSC%22&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1974-09-01&amp;end-date=1974-09-30&amp;sort-by=date-asc"
                                    >live example</a>
                            </blockquote>
                        </div>
                        <div id="single-year">
                            <h4>Single Year</h4>
                            <p>To search or filter results for all historical documents produced
                                during a particular year, use a date range search. For example, a
                                search for historical documents including the term “Russia“ and
                                dated sometime in 1917 should be entered as:</p>
                            <blockquote> Russia*<br/>
                                <hr/> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                                <hr/>
                                <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                    <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                                    <thead>
                                        <th>Month</th>
                                        <th>Day</th>
                                        <th>Year</th>
                                    </thead>
                                    <tr>
                                        <td>01</td>
                                        <td>01</td>
                                        <td>1917</td>
                                    </tr>
                                </table>
                                <hr/>
                                <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                    <caption><strong>End Date</strong></caption>
                                    <thead>
                                        <th>Month</th>
                                        <th>Day</th>
                                        <th>Year</th>
                                    </thead>
                                    <tr>
                                        <td>12</td>
                                        <td>31</td>
                                        <td>1917</td>
                                    </tr>
                                </table>
                                <hr/>
                                <a
                                    href="$app/search?q=Russia*&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1917-01-01&amp;end-date=1917-12-31&amp;sort-by=date-asc"
                                    >live example</a>
                            </blockquote>
                        </div>
                        <div id="year-range">
                            <h4>Year Range</h4>
                            <p>To search or filter results for all historical documents produced
                                during a particular range of years, use a date range search. For
                                example, a search for historical documents including the term
                                “union” dated sometime between 1861 and 1865 should be entered
                                as:</p>
                            <blockquote> union<br/>
                                <hr/> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                                <hr/>
                                <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                    <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                                    <thead>
                                        <th>Month</th>
                                        <th>Day</th>
                                        <th>Year</th>
                                    </thead>
                                    <tr>
                                        <td>01</td>
                                        <td>01</td>
                                        <td>1861</td>
                                    </tr>
                                </table>
                                <hr/>
                                <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                    <caption><strong>End Date</strong></caption>
                                    <thead>
                                        <th>Month</th>
                                        <th>Day</th>
                                        <th>Year</th>
                                    </thead>
                                    <tr>
                                        <td>12</td>
                                        <td>31</td>
                                        <td>1865</td>
                                    </tr>
                                </table>
                                <hr/>
                                <a
                                    href="search?q=union&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1861-01-01&amp;end-date=1865-12-31&amp;sort-by=relevance"
                                    >live example</a>
                            </blockquote>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div id="date-time-range">
                        <h3>Date and Time Range</h3>
                        <p>To search for all historical documents produced during a particular span
                            of dates and times, use a date and time range search. For example, a
                            search for all historical documents created or sent between noon on
                            August 9, 1974 and 6:30 am on August 10, 1974 should be entered as:</p>
                        <blockquote> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                            <hr/>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Month</th>
                                    <th>Day</th>
                                    <th>Year</th>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>08</td>
                                    <td>09</td>
                                    <td>1974</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>Start Time</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Hour</th>
                                    <th>Minute</th>
                                    <th/>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>12</td>
                                    <td>00</td>
                                    <td>◦ am ⦿ pm</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <hr/>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>End Date</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Month</th>
                                    <th>Day</th>
                                    <th>Year</th>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>08</td>
                                    <td>10</td>
                                    <td>1974</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                                <caption><strong>End Time</strong></caption>
                                <thead>
                                    <th>Hour</th>
                                    <th>Minute</th>
                                    <th/>
                                </thead>
                                <tr>
                                    <td>6</td>
                                    <td>30</td>
                                    <td>◦ am ⦿ pm</td>
                                </tr>
                            </table>
                            <hr/>
                            <a
                                href="$app/search?q=&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1974-08-09&amp;end-date=1974-08-10&amp;start-time=12:00&amp;end-time=18:30&amp;sort-by=date-asc"
                                >live example</a>
                        </blockquote>
                    </div>
                </div>

                <div id="volumes-filter">
                    <h2>Filtering By Volume (Alpha Release)</h2>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Volumes filters may be applied to searches within the Historical
                            Documents (<em>Foreign Relations</em> series) section of the site.</li>
                        <li>Volumes may be used in conjunction with keywords and/or dates or used
                            alone by leaving the search box blank.</li>
                        <li>Volume filters may be used at the beginning of a search or to refine the
                            results of a search.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>Taking the last example above, we can further refine the search results by
                        checking one or more <em>Foreign Relations</em> volumes of interest. For
                        example, a search for all historical documents created or sent between noon
                        on August 9, 1974 and 6:30 am on August 10, 1974 and limited to the
                            <em>1969–1976, Volume X, Vietnam, January 1973–July 1975</em> and
                            <em>1969–1976, Volume XXXV, National Security Policy, 1973–1976</em>
                        volumes should be entered as:</p>
                    <blockquote> ☑ Historical Documents<br/>
                        <hr/>
                        <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                            <caption><strong>Start Date</strong></caption>
                            <thead>
                                <th>Month</th>
                                <th>Day</th>
                                <th>Year</th>
                            </thead>
                            <tr>
                                <td>08</td>
                                <td>09</td>
                                <td>1974</td>
                            </tr>
                        </table>
                        <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                            <caption><strong>Start Time</strong></caption>
                            <thead>
                                <th>Hour</th>
                                <th>Minute</th>
                                <th/>
                            </thead>
                            <tr>
                                <td>12</td>
                                <td>00</td>
                                <td>◦ am ⦿ pm</td>
                            </tr>
                        </table>
                        <hr/>
                        <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                            <caption><strong>End Date</strong></caption>
                            <thead>
                                <th>Month</th>
                                <th>Day</th>
                                <th>Year</th>
                            </thead>
                            <tr>
                                <td>08</td>
                                <td>10</td>
                                <td>1974</td>
                            </tr>
                        </table>
                        <table style="border-collapse: separate; border-spacing: 10px;">
                            <caption><strong>End Time</strong></caption>
                            <thead>
                                <th>Hour</th>
                                <th>Minute</th>
                                <th/>
                            </thead>
                            <tr>
                                <td>6</td>
                                <td>30</td>
                                <td>◦ am ⦿ pm</td>
                            </tr>
                        </table>
                        <hr/> ☑ 1969–1976, Vietnam, January 1973–July 1975, Volume X<br/> ☑
                        1969–1976, National Security Policy, 1973–1976, Volume XXXV<br/>
                        <hr/>
                        <a
                            href="$app/search?q=&amp;volume-id=frus1969-76v10&amp;volume-id=frus1969-76v35&amp;within=documents&amp;start-date=1974-08-09&amp;end-date=1974-08-10&amp;start-time=12:00&amp;end-time=18:30&amp;sort-by=date-asc"
                            >live example</a>
                    </blockquote>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
