<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div data-template="pages:load">
        <div id="static-title" class="hidden">About Us</div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
                <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app">Home</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/about">About</a>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds">
                <div id="content-inner" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <h1>About Us</h1>
                    <p>Download our brochure (<a
                            href="https://static.history.state.gov/about/office-of-the-historian-brochure-2019.pdf"
                            >PDF, 1.6mb</a>).</p>
                    <div>
                        <h2>Who We Are</h2>
                        <p>The Office of the Historian is staffed by professional historians who are
                            experts in the history of U.S. foreign policy and the Department of
                            State and possess unparalleled research experience in classified and
                            unclassified government records. The Office’s historians work closely
                            with other federal government history offices, the academic historical
                            community, and specialists across the globe. The Office is directed by
                                <a href="$app/about/the-historian">The Historian of the U.S.
                                Department of State</a>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <h2>What We Do</h2>
                        <p>The Office of the Historian is responsible, under law, for the
                            preparation and publication of the official documentary history of U.S.
                            foreign policy in the <em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em>
                            series.</p>
                        <p>In addition, the Office prepares policy-supportive historical studies for
                            Department principals and other agencies. These studies provide
                            essential background information, evaluate how and why policies evolved,
                            identify precedents, and derive lessons learned. Department officers
                            rely on institutional memory, collective wisdom, and personal experience
                            to make decisions; rigorous historical analysis can sharpen, focus, and
                            inform their choices. The Office of the Historian conducts an array of
                            initiatives, ranging from briefing memos to multi-year research
                            projects.</p>
                        <p>The Office of the Historian also promotes the declassification of
                            documents to ensure a complete and accurate understanding of the
                            past.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <h2>
                            <em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em>
                        </h2>
                        <p>The <em>Foreign Relations of the United States</em> (<em>FRUS</em>)
                            series presents the official documentary historical record of major U.S.
                            foreign policy decisions. The series began in 1861 and now comprises
                            more than 480 individual volumes.</p>
                        <p>
                            <em>Foreign Relations</em> volumes contain documents from the
                            Presidential libraries, Departments of State and Defense, National
                            Security Council, Central Intelligence Agency, Agency for International
                            Development, and other foreign affairs agencies as well as the private
                            papers of individuals involved in implementing U.S. foreign policy.</p>
                        <p>Learn more about the series and view the collection at our <a
                                href="$app/historicaldocuments">Historical Documents</a> page.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <h2>Our Outreach Activities</h2>
                        <p>The Office’s public outreach activities include presenting at and hosting
                            scholarly conferences on key issues in the history of U.S. foreign
                            policy, answering historical research questions, and consulting with
                            scholars, educators, and students.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <h2>How to Access Our Materials</h2>
                        <p>The Office maintains a public website at <a href="/"
                                >history.state.gov</a>, which provides in-depth information to the
                            public on the history of U.S. foreign policy. In addition to a <a
                                href="$app/historicaldocuments">full text archive of the <em>Foreign
                                    Relations</em> series</a>, the website includes valuable
                            encyclopedic content on the history of <a href="$app/countries">U.S.
                                relations with states around the world</a>, and a database of the <a
                                href="$app/departmenthistory/people">Department’s principal officers
                                and chiefs of mission</a>.</p>
                        <p>In keeping with the Open Government Directive’s principle of
                            transparency, participation, and collaboration as the cornerstone of an
                            open government, all of the content and code on this site is available
                            for free download. The core repositories are available at <a
                                href="https://github.com/HistoryAtState">HistoryAtState</a> on
                            GitHub. Follow our progress, fork our code, file issues, and send us
                            your pull requests. The <a
                                href="https://github.com/HistoryAtState/hsg-project">hsg-project</a>
                            repository contains all instructions to install a complete copy of the
                            history.state.gov website on your own computer. Please visit our <a
                                href="$app/open">Open Government</a> page to learn more about our
                            contributions to data.gov.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
            <aside class="hsg-width-one-third" data-template="app:fix-links">
                <div class="hsg-panel">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">About</h2>
                    </div>
                    <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/about/contact-us">Contact Us</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/about/faq">Frequently Asked Questions</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/about/the-historian">The Historian</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/about/hac">Historical Advisory Committee</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/about/recent-publications">Recent Publications</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/about/content-warning">Content Warning</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
                <div class="hsg-panel">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h3 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Related Links</h3>
                    </div>
                    <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="https://twitter.com/HistoryAtState">@HistoryAtState on
                                Twitter</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="https://github.com/HistoryAtState">HistoryAtState on GitHub</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </aside>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
