<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div data-template="templates:surround" data-template-with="templates/site.xml"
    data-template-at="content">
    <div data-template="pages:load">
        <div id="static-title" class="hidden">Principal Officers and Chiefs of Mission - People -
            Department History</div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-breadcrumb-wrapper">
                <ol class="breadcrumb" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app">Home</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory">Department History</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people">People</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/principals-chiefs">Principal Officers
                            and Chiefs of Mission</a>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div class="row">
            <div class="hsg-width-two-thirds">
                <div id="content-inner" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <h1>Principal Officers and Chiefs of Mission</h1>
                    <div class="warning">
                        <p>
                            <strong>Note:</strong> The information presented here is for historical
                            research and is not necessarily up-to-date. The Department of State
                            maintains a list of current <a
                                href="https://www.state.gov/biographies-list/">Senior Officials</a>
                            and <a
                                href="https://www.state.gov/resources-bureau-of-global-talent-management/#ambassadors"
                                >Ambassadors</a>.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div class="contents">
                        <ul class="list-unstyled">
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/by-name">All Principal
                                    Officers and Chiefs of Mission, Listed by Name</a>
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/by-year">All Principal
                                    Officers and Chiefs of Mission, Listed by Year</a>
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/principalofficers">Principal
                                    Officers, Listed By Title</a>
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/chiefsofmission/by-country"
                                    >Chiefs of Mission, Listed by Country</a>
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                <a
                                    href="$app/departmenthistory/people/chiefsofmission/by-organization"
                                    >Chiefs of Mission, Listed By International Organization</a>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </div>
                    <h2 id="about">Introduction</h2>
                    <p>This online resource continues a long tradition in the U.S. Department of
                        State of making retrospective data about principal officers and chiefs of
                        mission available to the public. The 1873 edition of the <em>Register of the
                            Department of State</em> presented the names of all American diplomatic
                        representatives who had served in each country with which the United States
                        had relations from 1789 to 1873. The 1937 edition of the <em>Register</em>
                        presented a cumulative listing of all of the principal officers of the
                        Department of State from 1789 to 1936. The <em>Biographic Register</em> (as
                        the <em>Register of the United States</em> was renamed) of 1957 presented an
                        updated listing of principal diplomatic agents of the United States from
                        1789 to 1956, together with a listing of the dates of service of Presidents
                        of the United States and Secretaries of State. In 1973, the Department of
                        State issued <a href="https://hdl.handle.net/2027/txu.059172130110486"
                            >United States Chiefs of Mission, 1778−1973</a>, which presented in
                        tabular format a comprehensive historical listing of all United States
                        Ambassadors, Ministers, Ministers Resident, Chargés d’Affaires pro tempore,
                        and diplomatic agents. The publication also included a listing of principal
                        officers of the Department. The Department published <a
                            href="https://www.hathitrust.org/usdocs_registry/catalog/7a062c55-8462-45a0-a679-4cce574a9c40"
                            >United States Chiefs of Mission, 1973−1974 (Supplement)</a> in 1975
                        with addenda and corrigenda to the 1973 edition. <a
                            href="https://hdl.handle.net/2027/pur1.32754077529729">United States
                            Chiefs of Mission, 1778−1982</a> brought the full text to its second
                        edition.</p>
                    <p><a
                            href="https://www.hathitrust.org/usdocs_registry/catalog/d1433295-fdbd-4457-a683-bd877633aaa0"
                            >Principal Officers of the Department of State and United States Chiefs
                            of Mission, 1778−1986</a> issued by the Department of State in 1986,
                        presented expanded listings based on previous Department publications and
                        additional research and definition. Corrections were made to earlier
                        listings, and information on major executive officers of the Department of
                        State was greatly increased and rearranged. A revised edition, <a
                            href="https://www.hathitrust.org/usdocs_registry/catalog/a0971723-6d86-4d54-8b81-f77b8c584fbd"
                            >Principal Officers of the Department of State and United States Chiefs
                            of Mission, 1778−1988</a>, was issued in 1988. The final print version
                        of this publication was released in 1991, under the title <a
                            href="https://hdl.handle.net/2027/pur1.32754062053008">Principal
                            Officers of the Department of State and United States Chiefs of Mission,
                            1778−1990</a>. The transfer of this material online has not changed our
                        office’s intent: to document the history of U.S. representation abroad and
                        the chief policymakers in the Department of State. To that end, we have
                        provided a chronological listing of principal officers—essentially all
                        Department officers at the level of Assistant Secretary or above—and Chiefs
                        of Mission. (See below for a discussion of the term, “Chief of Mission.”)
                        These two categories require Presidential or Secretarial designation, and,
                        in some cases, the approval of the Senate. We have made an attempt to
                        comprehensively list all people selected for these positions, even if they
                        were not approved by the Senate, died before taking office, declined the
                        position, or were otherwise unable to serve. For that reason, the pages
                        which list our Chiefs of Mission by country are split into two categories:
                        “Chiefs of Mission” lists those who held the office, and “Other Nominees”
                        lists those who did not.</p>
                    <h3 id="positions-included">Positions Included</h3>
                    <p>This database includes officers of the Department who were Presidential
                        appointees (appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the
                        Senate) and chiefs of bureaus who hold rank equivalent to Assistant
                        Secretary of State. These include: Secretaries, Deputy Secretaries, Under
                        Secretaries, Deputy Under Secretaries, Assistant Secretaries, Counselors,
                        Legal Advisers, Chiefs of Protocol, and certain administrators.</p>
                    <p>Other positions have, from time to time, been included in the database based
                        on their particular circumstances. The complete lists of heads of the United
                        States Information Agency (USIA), for example, are included. USIA was
                        incorporated into the Department in 1999. Other Chiefs of Mission of
                        particular historical interest have also been included.</p>
                    <h3 id="positions-excluded">Positions Excluded</h3>
                    <p>This database does <em>not</em> include representatives, personal
                        representatives, or special representatives of the President or Department
                        of State; Chargés d’Affaires or Chargés d’Affaires ad interim (except under
                        certain circumstances); individuals holding diplomatic commissions jointly
                        with other representatives; special agents and other individuals on special
                        missions; high commissioners; Chiefs of Mission in charge of special
                        economic or aid missions; liaison officers; military governors or commanding
                        officers of occupying forces or their political advisers; delegates to
                        international conferences; or consular officers who held only consular
                        commissions.</p>
                    <h3 id="who-is-chief-of-mission">What is a Chief of Mission?</h3>
                    <p>According to the <a href="http://uscode.house.gov/statutes/pl/96/465.pdf"
                            >Foreign Affairs Act of 1980 (Public Law 96−465, Section 102(3) (22
                            U.S.C. 3902))</a>, a Chief of Mission is “the principal officer in
                        charge of a diplomatic mission of the United States or of a United States
                        office abroad which is designated by the Secretary of State as diplomatic in
                        nature, including any individual assigned under section 502(c) to be
                        temporarily in charge of such a mission or office."</p>
                    <p>The Chief of Mission is often—but not always—an Ambassador. There are
                        currently three classes of diplomatic representation established by the <a
                            href="https://2009-2017.state.gov/documents/organization/17843.pdf">1961
                            Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations, Article 14</a>: ambassador or
                        nuncio (accredited to the Head of State); envoy, minister, or internuncio
                        (accredited to the Head of State); and chargé d’affaires (accredited to the
                        Minister of Foreign Affairs). These classes have a much longer lineage.
                        Although not a signatory, the United States followed Annex 17 to the
                        Congress Treaty of Vienna (March 19, 1815), which established rank and
                        precedence of diplomatic agents (Ambassadors, Envoys, and Chargés
                        d’Affaires). The Proces-Verbal of the Conference of Aix-la-Chapelle
                        (November 9, 1818), recognized Ministers Resident as an intermediate class
                        between Ministers and Chargés d’Affaires.</p>
                    <p>The United States first used the rank of Ambassador in 1893, when <a
                            href="$app/departmenthistory/people/bayard-thomas-francis">Thomas F.
                            Bayard</a> was appointed Ambassador to Great Britain on March 30 of that
                        year.</p>
                    <p>A “Chargé d’Affaires ad interim” refers to a diplomat temporarily acting for
                        an absent Chief of Mission. This database tracks all Chargés d’Affaires and
                        Chargés d’Affaires ad interim who served (1) for a continuous period of 12
                        months or more, (2) at the establishment or ending of diplomatic relations
                        with a country, or (3) at the closure or opening of an embassy.</p>
                    <h3 id="database-contents">Database Contents</h3>
                    <p>The type of information included for each entry varies based on the type of
                        position. Entries will have some or all of these pieces of information:</p>
                    <dl>
                        <dt id="name">Name</dt>
                        <dd>When possible, the full name of the appointee has been included.</dd>
                        <dt id="years-of-birth-and-death">Years of birth and death</dt>
                        <dt id="state-of-residence">State of residency</dt>
                        <dd>The appointee’s state or territory of legal residence at the time of the
                            appointment is taken from the commission, nomination, or a contemporary
                            official record of legal residence. If the residence was omitted from
                            these sources, the entry does not appear. Some officers changed their
                            legal residence during their careers; in such cases multiple residences
                            are listed.</dd>
                        <dt id="career-status">Career status (in the Foreign Service)</dt>
                        <dd>The determination of which Chiefs of Mission were to be denominated as
                            “career” officers posed a number of problems to the early compilers of
                            this work, and continues to pose definitional challenges today. How
                            early could Chief of Mission appointments be said to be of a career
                            nature in view of the fact that until 1946 officers of the Diplomatic
                            Service had to resign from the career services to accept appointment as
                            Ambassador or Minister? Should an officer who had retired as a Foreign
                            Service officer after a long career be considered a “career” officer
                            when later appointed to an Ambassadorship? And what of an officer who
                            had resigned from the Foreign Service after a brief career who was later
                            appointed Chief of Mission? At the time the scope and format of this
                            publication were being planned, a dozen such questions were submitted to
                            the then-Director General of the Foreign Service. It was determined not
                            to attempt to categorize Chiefs of Mission as “career” or “non-career”
                            before the passage of the Act to Improve the Foreign Service on February
                            5, 1915 (38 Stat. 805), which restructured the Diplomatic and Consular
                            Services. For Chiefs of Mission holding office as such at that date, it
                            was decided to count as “career” those who had at least ten years of
                            continuous diplomatic service under both Republican and Democratic
                            administrations. For Chiefs of Mission appointed later, the term
                            “career” was also applied to those who were at the time of appointment
                            (or had previously been for at least five years) Foreign Service
                            officers, Foreign Service information officers, or career officers in
                            the Diplomatic or Consular Services. The term “career” was also applied
                            to those few individuals who had served as diplomatic secretaries, who
                            had then been commissioned before 1915 as Chiefs of Mission or as
                            Presidential appointees in the Department of State, who were not serving
                            as Chiefs of Mission in February 1915, but who were subsequently
                            appointed or reappointed as such. The term “non-career” is used to
                            designate all other appointees even though they may have been career
                            officers in the civil or military services.</dd>
                        <dt id="dates-of-service">Dates of service</dt>
                        <dd>These dates are included on a position-by-position basis. Principal
                            officers of the Department of State who are Presidential appointees have
                            a date of appointment, date of entry on duty, and date of termination of
                            appointment. Chiefs of Mission are considered to have entered on duty
                            when they present their credentials to their host governments. An effort
                            has been made to fix a date for the termination of the diplomatic
                            mission of each representative vis-à-vis the host government and to
                            describe briefly in each individual case (and as precisely as sometimes
                            incomplete records permit) what action or event brought the mission to
                            either a formal or a de facto close. In the nineteenth century it was
                            customary for a Chief of Mission to present his own letter of recall; in
                            current practice most missions terminate in actual fact with the
                            departure of the Ambassador from his or her post. In all periods there
                            have been special circumstances (e.g., death, declaration of war,
                            severance of diplomatic relations) which have brought some diplomatic
                            missions to an end. It should be emphasized that the effective date of a
                            Chief of Mission's resignation frequently does not coincide with the
                            date shown here for the termination of his or her mission abroad. For
                            those who were designated by the Secretary of State, the date of
                            appointment is the same as the date of entry on duty. For Chargés
                            d’Affaires ad interim, dates of service are listed from and to the
                            nearest month.</dd>
                    </dl>
                    <h3 id="key-terms">Key Terms</h3>
                    <dl>
                        <dt id="appointment">Appointment</dt>
                        <dd>The date of appointment is that which appears upon the face of the
                            Presidential commission issued to the appointee. It is frequently
                            referred to as the date of commissioning or the date of attestation.
                            Recess appointments are valid only until the end of the current session
                            of the Senate. If the President wishes to keep a recess appointee in
                            office, the President must re-nominate the appointee.</dd>
                        <dt id="commission">Commission</dt>
                        <dd>A document attesting that the appointee has been appointed as a
                            principal officer of the Department of State or as a Chief of Mission.
                            It is signed by the President and the Secretary of State and bears the
                            impression of the Great Seal of the United States. “Commission” always
                            connotes Presidential action.</dd>
                        <dt id="designation">Designation</dt>
                        <dd>This term covers chiefs of bureaus of the Department of State who are
                            selected by the Secretary of State. Article II, Section 2 of the
                            Constitution states that “the Congress may by law vest the Appointment
                            of such inferior Officers, as they think proper, in the President alone,
                            in the Courts of Law, or in the Heads of Departments.” “Designation”
                            always connotes Secretarial action.</dd>
                        <dt id="nomination">Nomination</dt>
                        <dd>This is the date that the President sends to the Senate the name of a
                            person whom he wishes to appoint to a high-level position. Article II,
                            Section 2 of the Constitution states that the President, “by and with
                            the Advice and Consent of the Senate, shall appoint Ambassadors, other
                            public Ministers and Consuls, Judges of the supreme Court, and all other
                            Officers of the United States, whose Appointments are not herein
                            otherwise provided for, and which shall be established by Law.” Per <a
                                href="https://www.rules.senate.gov/rules-of-the-senate">Senate Rule
                                XXXI</a>, “Nominations neither confirmed nor rejected during the
                            session at which they are made shall not be acted upon at any succeeding
                            session without being again made to the Senate by the President; and if
                            the Senate shall adjourn or take a recess for more than thirty days, all
                            nominations pending and not finally acted upon at the time of taking
                            such adjournment or recess shall be returned by the Secretary to the
                            President, and shall not again be considered unless they shall again be
                            made to the Senate by the President.”</dd>
                    </dl>
                    <h3 id="steps-in-appointment">Steps in Appointment</h3>
                    <p>Nomination is the first step in the appointment process. The President
                        submits the name of the person to be appointed to a high-level position to
                        the Senate for approval by first the Foreign Relations Committee and then by
                        the full Senate. Approval by the full Senate is called “confirmation.” The
                        appointee is then commissioned. After taking the oath of office, he or she
                        enters on duty. Chiefs of Mission, however, are considered to have entered
                        on duty when they present their credentials to their host governments.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            <aside class="hsg-width-one-third">
                <div id="sections" class="hsg-panel" data-template="app:fix-links">
                    <div class="hsg-panel-heading">
                        <h2 class="hsg-sidebar-title">Department History</h2>
                    </div>
                    <ul class="hsg-list-group">
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/timeline">Administrative Timeline of the
                                Department of State</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/buildings">Buildings of the
                                Department</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people">People</a>
                            <ul>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/secretaries">Biographies
                                        of the Secretaries of State</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/people/principals-chiefs"
                                        >Principal Officers and Chiefs of Mission</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels">Travels</a>
                            <ul>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels/secretary">Travels of
                                        the Secretary</a>
                                </li>
                                <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                                    <a href="$app/departmenthistory/travels/president">Travels of
                                        the President</a>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/visits">Visits by Foreign Leaders</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/wwi">World War I and the Department</a>
                        </li>
                        <li class="hsg-list-group-item">
                            <a href="$app/departmenthistory/diplomatic-couriers">U.S. Diplomatic
                                Couriers</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </aside>
        </div>
    </div>
</div>
